

CONTACT

- Yunusabad 9, 68, Tashkent,Uzbekistan 100190
- 998994387586
- alijanovbakhtiyor@gmail.com
- Uzbek
- https://bakhtiyordev.github.io/portfolio-deployed/
- in www.linkedin.com/in/bakhtiyor-dev

SKILLS

- Design patterns and principles
- Object-oriented PHP
- API design knowledge
- E-commerce background
- Active Directory
- Database management software
- SQL
- PHP
- HTML coding
- Web-based software engineering
- GitHub
- CSS
- Front and back end development

Bakhtiyor Alijanov

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Solution-driven developer adept at contributing to highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions and determining customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused websites using HTML, CSS, PHP and JavaScript. Built products users over 2+ years, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices and speed. Designed and developed web applications across multiple APIs, third-party integrations and databases.

WORK HISTORY

PHP Web Developer

04/2022 - 03/2023

Wasaf - Tashkent, Uzbekistan

- Boosted website performance and stability through planned maintenance and targeted troubleshooting.
- Developed and tested REST APIs to check API responds with wide variety of requests.
- Harnessed emerging technologies to develop innovative and profitable products
- Implemented cyber security best practices to achieve stable systems.
- Facilitated code reviews and pair programming to produce clean, highquality code.

PHP Developer

03/2021 - 04/2022

Mdsoft - Tashkent, Uzbekistan

- Developed and tested REST APIs to check API responds with wide variety of requests.
- Managed databases with strong SQL skills.
- Created custom websites by harnessing HTML, CSS and JavaScript skills.
- Wrote and updated software documentation to help users better understand site.
- Maximised quality of product, creating and maintaining accurate software development documentation.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science: Software Engineering, 09/2019 – Current **Tashkent University of Information Technologies** – Tashkent/Uzbekistan